I'm Peppa Pig. [snorts]
-This is my little brother, George.
-[snorts]
-This is Mommy Pig.
-[Mommy Pig snorts]
And this is Daddy Pig.
-[Daddy Pig snorts]
-[all laugh]
Peppa Pig. [snorts]
[Peppa reads on-screen text]
[narrator] Peppa and George are at Granny
and Grandpa Pig's house.
[Peppa & George giggling]
-[Peppa] Grandpa Pig!
-[George] Grandpa Ig!
Oh, what's this?
A cuckoo clock?
Yes, it goes:
"Cuckoo, cuckoo!"
But it's broken.
[snorts] Can you mend it please,
Grandpa Pig?
Hmm. [snorts]
Let's take it to my shed.
[narrator] This is Grandpa Pig's shed,
where Grandpa mends things.
I'll take a look inside.
Grandpa!
Now you've really broken it.
Oh.
I wonder if I've got a book on clocks.
Ah, here we are.
How Clocks Work.
[narrator] Grandpa Pig has mended
the cuckoo clock.
[Peppa & George] Hooray!
[bird cuckoos]
[Peppa & George giggle]
-[Peppa & George cuckooing]
-[Grandpa Pig laughing]
[horn honks]
[narrator] Mommy Pig has come
to pick up Peppa and George.
[snorts] Mommy,
Grandpa's mended the cuckoo clock!
That's nice. [snorts]
What's that?
It's my old computer.
[snorts] I can't mend that.
It's not broken.
I've got a new computer.
I thought you might like my old one.
Um, I'm not sure I really need one.
Oh, a computer.
What does it do?
You can do letters with it.
Look, Granny.
[computer] A, B, C, D.
And numbers.
[computer] One, two, three.
I'm afraid we might break it
by pressing the wrong button.
[chuckles] Don't worry.
You can't break it.
Just don't feed it milk
or biscuits or jelly.
[all laugh]
The best thing it does
is "Happy Mrs. Chicken."
[George snorts]
When you press this button,
she lays an egg.
[chicken clucks & farts]
I am very good at it,
[snorts] but George is the best.
-[George giggling]
-[chicken clucking and farting]
[all laughing]
That's fun.
Uh, perhaps, we should keep the computer,
Granny Pig.
-[grandparents] Goodbye.
-[Mommy Pig & children] Bye-bye.
[horn honks]
Shall we do some work
on the computer, Granny Pig?
Yes, let's do some numbers and letters.
[narrator] Peppa and her family
are having lunch.
I've given my old computer
to Granny and Grandpa.
That's nice.
I wonder how they're getting on with it.
[phone rings]
Hello, Peppa Pig speaking.
Uh, Peppa, I need to ask a question
about the computer.
It's Grandpa.
He's broken the computer.
What's the problem
with the computer, Grandpa Pig?
-It's full of eggs.
-Eggs?
Happy Mrs. Chicken won't lay
any more eggs.
[computer beeps]
[computer] I'm broken.
Turn the computer off.
Now turn it back on again.
Did that fix it?
[computer beeping]
[computer] I am very broken.
That doesn't sound good.
Maybe it can't be mended.
We'll come round and pick it up.
[computer beeping]
Granny, we're here
to take the computer back.
Oh. Grandpa Pig has taken it to his shed.
There, that should do it.
[computer] I am mended.
[Peppa & George] Hooray!
[snorts] My grandpa is the best
at mending things.
Was it very hard to mend?
Not at all.
I found I had this book,
How Computers Work.
You don't want us to take it away now?
No. I need it for important work.
For letter and number work?
[snorts] No.
To beat Granny Pig's
"Happy Mrs. Chicken" score.
I laid 4020 eggs.
[all] Wow.
So, I've got some work to do catching up.
[clucking and farting]
[all laughing]
[Peppa reads on-screen text]
[narrator] Peppa, George and Danny
are having a day out
on Granddad Dog's boat.
[woofs] Can we go to Pirate Island today?
Yes, Danny.
But first, we've got to deliver supplies
to my friend Grampy Rabbit.
Where does Grampy Rabbit live?
-On a rock.
-On a rock?
Yes. In that lighthouse.
[children] Ooh.
Ahoy there, matey.
I've brought your supplies.
Oh. Thank you, Granddad Dog.
I've got my crew with me today.
Danny, Peppa and George.
Visitors?
I haven't had visitors in many a moon.
I get a bit lonely with just the sea
and sky for company.
How long have you been here?
-Since Tuesday.
-Oh.
I've got tales to tell,
if you'd like to hear.
-No, thanks.
-[children] Yes, please.
Well, there's the sea and the sky, and--
I'm learning the banjo.
Would you like to hear a song?
-No, thanks.
-[children] Yes, please.
♪ I got up this morning ♪
♪ The sea was still there ♪
♪ So was the sky ♪
♪ The sea, the sky, the sea, the sky ♪
[Granddad Dog] Here's your cheese.
-Oh. I've missed cheese.
-And a new book.
How to Run a Lighthouse.
Oh, that'll come in handy.
Why is your house called a lighthouse?
I'll show you, Peppa.
[narrator] The staircase goes round
and round
to the very top of the lighthouse.
[snorts] Round and round and round.
It's called a lighthouse
because it has this big light at the top.
[children] Wow!
[Grampy Rabbit] It shines through
the dark,
helping sailors to find their way.
[children] Ooh.
And when it's foggy, I use this foghorn.
Fog!
That's loud.
No fog today, just sea and sky.
The stories I could tell--
[Granddad Dog] No, thank you.
We've got to go.
[snorts] We're sailing to Pirate Island.
[children] Goodbye, Grampy Rabbit.
Enjoy the sea and the sky!
[children] We will.
[horn toots]
[narrator] Granddad Dog's boat has arrived
at Pirate Island.
Look, our sand castle is still here.
Let's play hide-and-seek.
Okay.
One, two, three...
[narrator] There are not many places
to hide on Pirate Island.
Ready or not, here I come.
-[Danny woofs]
-Found you.
-[Danny & Peppa] Oh.
-Now, where's George?
[children giggling]
[narrator] Granddad Dog
cannot find George anywhere.
-I give up. Where is he?
-Boo!
[narrator] George was hiding
behind Granddad Dog.
-Clever George.
-[George snorts]
Let's set off home, before it gets dark.
Oh, it is getting dark.
Don't worry.
The light from Grampy Rabbit's lighthouse
will show us the way home.
[narrator] Grampy Rabbit is ready for bed.
Oh, my new book,
How to Run a Lighthouse.
"Chapter One."
[yawns]
I'll read the rest tomorrow.
Better turn the light out.
[Peppa] Oh, where did the light go?
[ringing]
Do you know what time it is?
I've turned the lights out.
Yes, we know.
Could you turn the big light on again?
Oh, sorry.
[all] Hooray!
[narrator] It is getting foggy.
I can't see the light anymore.
It's us again.
Could you sound the foghorn?
[Grampy Rabbit] Of course.
Fog!
-I can hear something.
-[Grampy Rabbit] Fog!
[narrator] Grampy Rabbit
is guiding them home.
-His voice is a foghorn.
-[Grampy Rabbit] This way! This way home!
[narrator] The parents are here
to pick up the children.
-Have you had a lovely time?
-We went to Pirate Island.
And to a lighthouse.
Grampy Rabbit's lighthouse
guided us home safely.
That's nice.
Grampy Rabbit sang a song.
Would you like to hear it?
-No, thanks.
-[parents] Yes, please.
♪ I got up this morning ♪
♪ The sea was still there ♪
♪ So was the sky ♪
♪ The sea, the sky, the sea, the sky ♪
[children giggling]